Chess Grand Masters seen as calculative machines
Ding Lee Ren's loss made people realize the human element
Ding is beloved in the chess community
Ding is the highest rated Chinese Grandmaster in history
Ding became the highest rated Blitz player in the world
Ding's personality attracts people
Ding is known for his humility and emotions
Ding competes for the world championship
Ding tries his best under great stress
Ding keeps things respectful and lighthearted in interviews
Ding drew a match despite leaked preparation
Ding's integrity is worthy of respect
Ding receives an explosion of support after the leak
Ding is an underdog worth supporting in the tournament