we are expecting a repetition at this
point we're doing falling back with the
King to G8 Rook G6 is not a move that
you consider here right it's the only
move that I feel with black keeps the
game going but it looks like more like a
losing move than a winning attempt
the fruit G6 is not better for what I'd
be shocked but it's not definitely oh my
God what
for a win
the rent tried to win this game because
this is a big moment the bishop on E3 is
pinned the Queens are looking at each
other through that Bishop so if you
can't take on C5 black is up a pawn and
dingley Wren I keep using this Hemingway
uh expression you know he said courage
is Grace Under Pressure he's courageous
and queen of five use black the upper
hand apparently
yeah is he just pushing but but wait why
would white black be better here
uh you push with C4 yeah that's
actually C4 C4 is
on the board why it's got to go H4 H5
right that's the plan but black stops it
with H5
or queen G4 as well you could try to
trade Queens you are up two queen side
passers and we keep talking about Blitz
this is about to be a Blitz game where
yonda palmchi is currently up almost a
minute but he is down a pawn and those
are some scary pawns to be down I'm in
absolute shock that Ding actually
decided to continue the game with just a
minute on the clock he's refused their
repetition going into Blitz
yeah this is a pretty wild decision
Maybe
it actually looks like a brilliant
decision but probably because this queen
F5 was was a mistake
um and maybe he just missed C4 he
thought he's picking up that pawn but
he's not picking up that pawn
so what does he do Bishop
D4
I just want to stop C3 there
Queen D3 yeah
yeah Queen D3
oh my gosh this is a position where Jan
might have only one move to survive I I
see the eval bar saying 0.3 but that is
completely misleading everybody there
are two separate pass pawns most
importantly there's Advanced C pawn and
you want to rush upon H5 you do not get
that the queen steps to G4 after Pawn HR
offering a queen trade and then the pawn
goes up to C3 Bobby Tanya this is
worrisome territory for Jana Pomchi
who's dipping to just about a minute and
that was a mistake
oh Queen D3 not even Queen G4 Queen D3
that's the best way
yeah that that's really really bad for
white
oh my goodness the C3 is happening move
Rook G6 we were thinking that's not even
a possibility and such a brave decision
and it's paying off ding Loren with the
reval bar it shows that he's clearly
better better here but practically Fabi
how easy is this in um with a minute on
the clock and Jan there keeps the Queens
on the board which is absolutely crucial
for any play with white he has to get H5
in Rook D1 like it's just pushing like
what does the H5 matter because you
don't give checks on the diagonal
anymore
like
oh
okay
C3 F6
it doesn't seem to change a huge amount
yeah what are you doing here as white
because the queen on D3 is so well
positioned and I he goes Rook D1 he
wants to chase the Queen off the
diagonal I think that's a good choice
just slide back to F5 and then Queen C4
he has to to engineer some sort of Rook
d8 Rook D5 like something with activity
oh but I like this because if Queen C4
this Rook C6 now the queen and Rook
along the sixth rank helps to push the
pawn
that's a good move so wait does the
Queen have to go to E2
but that's not what you want to do
because then Rook C6 anyway with the
threat of C2 Bishop to A3 and he's also
has no time
oh wow so yeah this is very very close
oh my goodness we're stunned into
silence maybe you need to play Queen E2
quickly and just pray
I mean obviously your position is bad
uh but at least keep some time on the
clock he's down to 35 seconds ding's the
one with the time Advantage Fabi
yeah well white has to keep some time on
the clock just in case it turns into a
mess at some point wait now Rook C6 what
is even the idea is he gonna try to
sacrifice a piece and go for an attack
against this King that should not pan
out but maybe this Kings have tried to
hide on H2 and in a scramble if it gets
into real time trouble for black when
you under attack that's when mistakes
happen
yeah maybe good practical shot I mean
for sure this psac is his idea uh it
doesn't work like all these things are
definitely true but
like
he wants to avoid it so
we're now Rook to C1 at least
or wait can you trade maybe you could
trade
oh let's give him a question mark you
can trade and then try to get your queen
back to E4 at some point try to make it
just try to like hold a move by move
yeah Queen E4 Queen C4 and it's not an
it's not a media drawer but you're
saying black cannot easily progress
because the
and he finds it here we need four Queen
G6 Queen C4 good good try
and not only C2 a good practice let's
try sorry Fabi but look at the eval bar
it says minus 1.4 or is it nearly minus
four so Jan may be fighting back in this
game just when it looked like dingley
Wren would be crowned world champion
well it's very difficult to advance that
pawn because C2 is allowing H5 ideas
and if not C2 then maybe you play H5
with black here maybe you really need to
get those light squares under control
okay you can give a check it probably
doesn't change a whole lot because you
want to stop anything
pushing the a pawn maybe maybe but then
Bishop to
somewhere Bishop D4 will get some
counter play Maybe King goes to H2 not
to allow Queen E4 check although
probably doesn't change much
goodness King H2 is played and look at
the eval bar it's going near level this
could be dangerous for for a ding if
he's all In For the Win he could find
himself under pressure with his G7 Pawn
targeted by the bishop on D4 as well
yeah I mean like Bishop D4 C2 maybe you
lose because of Queen uh to F7 yeah
something like that obviously you never
you would never want to allow but
generally speaking black does not risk
here but Bishop D4 the point of the King
on H2 Queen E4 was not checked because
Queen takes B4 wins a piece 17 seconds
and that was correct one wait A3 and
oh is he going back queen of seven Queen
B3
or is the queen of Southern Queen C4
yeah uh Queen G6 is available I think
that's what you we're indicating the
pawns protected he goes Queen 27 which
is a mistake a huge mistake in time
travel from Beyond the Palm Tree the
queen has to go back to G6 that's the
good news for dingley red he has only
one move here and Jan is the one down to
20 seconds and counting down
wait Bishop C3
oh which is A2 and queen B1 man there's
no checks yeah yeah that's
yeah I think this is over
oh my God Queen C4 back it's the only
only move
will he find it the only way to keep the
game going is Queen back to C4 going
after the bishop he plays just that so
good find C2 now yeah this is
so close to disaster
what he's holding on right now is Bishop
C5 oh no it's not I was trying to get
too clever Bishop D6 this H4 Pawn may be
hanging in some positions he goes King
G2 which keeps it in minus three so
that's obviously an advantage for black
but maybe it's time Fabi for your H5
move just because you don't want this
King to be checked uh left and right you
know non-stop so maybe H5 helps that
King
just to stop white because white is
there any H5 now it white has a threat
of H5 H5 queen of five G4 and the queen
has to lose contact with the C2 Pawn H5
uh might not be an easy decision because
you feel like if my Queen ever gets
active then white will Target that H
Pawn definitely a difficult decision but
might be the right move
if he plays H5 why we'll play Queen to
D5
H5 Queen do you find the oh I was gonna
say A2 but you can just take my Pawn
yeah it doesn't work that works because
Queen E4 take this bishop
oh yeah he can actually play A2
immediately
although you'd be very careful here
let's see King F1 oh I don't think the
king in the belongs the first rank that
means a pawn might promote with check at
some point
wait now King E2 Queen G4 so you can't
move your king but he was avoiding this
A2 Queen E4 Queen E3 because he saw that
option he was avoiding it with King F1
boy now Bishop to B2 is coming this is
just game over I mean there's no more
hope here the bishop on V2 white doesn't
even have counter play
he's going for just desperation
for the H5 Queen F5 yeah this is
desperation is not working out ding is
going to win this match unbelievable
the resilience from dingley Ren he
brings his Queen up now it's on F5
there's a pass Pawn C2 that's defended
you can't distract the queen anymore
dingley run who is down a point in this
match is he about to become a world
champion
foreign
do anything here
I mean he doesn't have to panic but he
can play A2 oh
Queen D3 probably wins G3 probably wins
yeah
and now A2 A2 is super super winning
not even hope he's left we're just
seconds away from thing becoming the
world champion if he just plays the next
few accurate moves it's all over
I just want to move A2 and it's over
and it's on the board
oh my goodness
he sits up in his chair but he knows
this might be the last few moves of his
world championship oh my God
oh you see it he knows
he knows it
yeah Bishop takes F4 is easy
heartbreaking
it's over dingling is the world just
champion
wow he has made history as the first
Chinese player to win the World
Championship we see handshakes that Ding
is overtaken by emotions he isn't able
to leave the board and for yeah a
heartbreaking moment there he leaves the
hall this has been a fight of Courage of
grit and determination and all of that
has paid off for dingler and take a
moment and admire ding right now what a
match this has been and a deserving
victory for dingler in yes 2023 world
champion