foreign
is something very extraordinary I think
it's the most important event in chess
he represents the highest level of
professional chess there are only two
players that plays this match and of
course every single player dreams about
getting the sacred place I hope there
will be more decisive games this time
the whole world will be cheering getting
geared up and immersed in the World
Chess Championship uh you know like this
Kung Fu Panda cartoon yeah like there is
no secret ingredient in my soup it's a
big challenge for me but I'm ready for
this challenge
[Music]
game was a beautiful one today is the
game was a disaster
just sack The Exchange just do it hold
on this was insane very big comeback
from getting
I mean this is incredible stuff this is
like a master class Mr Dean is actually
playing an absolutely perfect game at
chess's wife five minutes for the Knicks
eight moves and he has to come up with a
plan somehow just make a move this will
be yeah yeah
and the final game ends in a draw the
fide World Chess Championship will be
decided by a tie break
this is the most exciting world
championship match we have had in a damn
long time
all come on oh wow wow oh actually ding
is going for the win does this man is
brilliant
I'll say I think this is the end
we need a world championship
dramatic thrilling World Chess
championships ever
thank you
foreign
[Music]