not to allow Queen for check although
probably doesn't change much
my goodness King H2 is played and look
at the eval bar it's going near level
this could be dangerous for for ding if
he's all In For the Win he could find
himself under pressure with his G7 Pawn
targeted by the bishop on D4 as well
yeah I mean like Bishop D4 C2 maybe you
lose because of Queen uh to F7 something
like that obviously you never you never
want to allow but generally speaking
black does not risk here but Bishop D4
the point of the King on H2 Queen E4 was
not checked because Queen takes B4 wins
a piece 17 seconds
and that was correct one wait A3 and
oh is he going back queen of seven Queen
B3
or is it a queen of Southern Queen C4
yeah uh Queen G6 is available I think
that's what you we're indicating that
pawns protecting he goes Queen C7 which
is a mistake a huge mistake in time
travel from Beyond the Palm Tree the
queen has to go back to G6 that's the
good news for dingley red he has only
one move here and Jan is the one down to
20 seconds and counting down
wait Bishop C3
oh which is A2 and queen B1 then there's
no checks yeah yeah that's
yeah I think this is over
only move
will he find it the only way to keep the
game going is Queen back to C4 going
after the bishop he plays just that so
good find C2 now yeah this is
oh my gosh so close to disaster
but he's holding on right now oh is
Bishop C5 oh no it's not I was trying to
get too clever Bishop D6 this H4 Pawn
may be hanging in some positions he goes
King G2 which keeps it in -3 so that's
obviously an advantage for black but
maybe it's time Fabi for your H5 move
just because you don't want this King to
be checked uh left and right you know
non-stop so maybe H5 helps that King
just to stop white because white is
there any H5 now a white has a threat of
H5 H5 queen of five G4 and the queen has
to lose contact with C2 Pawn H5
uh might not be an easy decision because
you feel like if my Queen ever gets
active then white will Target that H
Pawn definitely a difficult decision
well it might be the right move
if he plays H5 why we'll play Queen to
D5
H5 Queen D5 oh I was gonna say A2 but
you can just take my Pawn yeah it
doesn't work that works there's Queen E4
take this bishop oh yeah he can actually
play A2 immediately
although you'd be very careful here
let's see King F1 oh I don't think the
king of the belongs the first rank that
means a pawn might promote with check at
some point
wait now King E2 Queen G4 so you can't
move your king oof but he was avoiding
this A2 Queen E4 Queen E3 because he saw
that option he was avoiding it with King
F1 oh wait now Bishop to B2 is coming
this is just game over I mean there's no
more hope here the bishop on V2 white
doesn't even have counter play
he's going for just desperation
with a H5 Queen F5 yeah this is
desperation is not working out ding is
going to win this match unbelievable
the resilience from dingley Ren he
brings his Queen up now it's on F5
there's a pass Pawn C2 that's defended
you can't distract the queen anymore
dingly run who is down a point in this
match is he about to become a world
champion
uh well I can do anything here
I mean he doesn't have to panic but he
can play A2 uh
in D3 probably wins G3 probably wins
yeah and now A2 A2 is super super
winning
not even hope he's left just seconds
away from ding becoming the world
champion if he just plays the next few
accurate moves it's all over
just one move A2 and it's over
oh my goodness and yeah
up in his chair but he knows this might
be the last few moves of his world
championship oh my God
oh you see it
he knows it
yeah Bishop takes F4 is easy
heartbreaking
it's over dingling is the world just
champion
wow he has made history as the first
Chinese player to win the World
Championship we see handshakes that Ding
is overtaken by emotions he isn't able
to leave the board and for yeah a
heartbreaking moment there he leaves the
hall this has been a fight of Courage of
grit and determination and all of that
has paid off for dingler and take a
moment and admire ding right now what a
match this has been and a deserving
victory for dingler in yes 2023 world
champion