yeah I think Robert you you called it
right before the game started it's it
this is the d word
we're heading for a draw
you know I there's there's no reason to
writ look he's trading everything off he
had a slightly better position he could
have played on but what he is doing is
he's simplifying the Queens are about to
come off so just to draw
seven
and he comes back with the Rook 35
that's a Ted Time repetition we will see
the players call out for an Avida to
check that
as it's not allowed to offer a draw in
this position so the Orbiter would
usually come and ensure that in fact the
position has been repeated Thrice
a little awkward pause there between Yan
ending as they wait for the Orbiter to
arrive the game has ended in a draw
are they supposed to be in a few seconds
yeah it's funny they have to ask for
permission to make a draw when they're
very obviously in a position that is uh
drawn and yeah there's the handshake it
is a split point which means Jana
palmshi keeps his one point advantage