hello
i am jenny at the chess kids so i have
questions for you
guys
when he went here
so right now i'm talking english when
everybody understood us
so uh what you can recommend of the
chess kids who want to be strong chess
players
sorry can you speak your question again
repeat your question again very sorry
okay
in english i will repeat so uh
what you can recommend at the chess kids
who want to be strong chess players my
comments just kids what do you recommend
to just kids to become strong players
first you need to
love this game
you
you're willing to willing to spend more
time on it
yeah when i was young
when i finished my homework
[Laughter]
when i was younger
yeah i spent the rest of my time
studying chess following tournament
online and also sometimes i
play some games with
my friends
and i think that's the most important
thing that you are willing to spend some
time on chance thank you
you