we sometimes think of Chess Grand
Masters as machines able to calculate
and remember all the possible moves in a
position but when ding Lee Ren froze in
game 7 of the world championship causing
him to lose it made viewers realize that
we are dealing with people that have
spent a huge amount of their life
polishing their skills and following
their passion for chess sure most of us
cannot relate to being a chess
Grandmaster but we can relate to
freezing or struggling Under Pressure
that is what made the support for ding
even more heartwarming and to be honest
I wasn't familiar with ding as a player
or his history so I asked myself why is
ding so beloved in the chess community
and here's what I found ding lyron born
in 1992 is the highest rated Chinese
chess Grandmaster in history that on its
own is an amazing feat but he doesn't
stop there in July 2016 with a blitz
rating of 2875
5 he managed to become the highest rated
Blitz player in the world and right now
he is competing for the world
championship but to the chess Community
ding is more than his achievements it's
normal for Grandmasters to shine on the
board but they also have a way of
attracting people with their
personalities take Magnus Carlson for
example he is the best player in the
world but a lot of people love him for
his trolling and sometimes really clever
jokes another one is Hikaru while known
in the Chess World as the best defender
he's also known for liking drama a bit
too much but ding is often accompanied
with humility when asked about his
preparation for game one he said I
didn't prepare anything yesterday
because I'm struggling with my my
feelings my emotions you can tell from
the interview and the games that Ding is
a very emotional person who is under
great stress but that doesn't stop him
from trying his best when asked about
the reason of there being so many
decisive matches in the tournament ding
replied by being humble and saying maybe
we are not professional like Magnus
while the question might have been out
of place ding managed to keep things
respectful and lighthearted but this
interview of game 8 made everyone fall
for dank my climatechess.com my question
is for Grandmaster ding Loren
um I suspect you might know this is
coming
some people online have found games
played on Lee chess that match very
closely with some games played here
what is your reaction to this rumor
I don't know I don't know
ding drew the match with white and he
very well could have attributed the draw
to the leaked preparation but he did not
he did not ruin Ian's lead in the
tournament to the chess community that
is worthy of respect besides that a lot
of people started to feel bad that this
happened to him but this leak also
caused an explosion of support for ding
that you don't really see that often in
chess I have recently seen a lot of
support for ding to win it all and
honestly I feel the same after all who
doesn't love an Underdog Story